Matthew Dingee

User Experience Designer

PROFILE

I am a designer with a focus on rapid HTML/CSS/JS prototyping to demonstrate responsive site designs.

I have worked on many large-scale client libraries (Cisco, Marriott, Yahoo) and led several responsive design projects. I bridge the gap from designer to front-end development and help teams ship.

User Experience Designer

Software Developer

Information Architect

EXPERIENCE

EightShapes, LLC

Senior Interaction Designer November 2011 - July 2015 (3 years, 9 months) Contributed to the creation and management of the design system that allowed Marriott to make their site responsive and to drive reservations on mobile devices.

Designed and produced a prototype of the membership renewal process for NCARB.

Designed and built many of the responsive components behind Cisco's Unified Computing Servers product category.

Responsible for stabilizing and enhancing the EightShapes Blocks prototyping framework.

Wrote the Javascript code behind The Heritage Guide to the Constitution site, an app with the Constitution as the focus.

Microsoft Corporation

Senior Software Engineer,
Business Solutions
Engineering/Network & Cloud
November 2008 - May 2011
(2 years, 7 months)

Interaction designer for VoIP SIP URI provisioning in the Tellme Platform Central product.

Lead software engineer responsible for implementing the Tellme Platform Central product.

Tellme Networks

Senior Software Engineer, Platform Engineering October 2001 - October 2008 Interaction designer for internal VoIP traffic management.

Co-designed, built, and deployed an internal web application for viewing call traffic on the Tellme Network.

Co-designed, built, and deployed an internal web application for the provisioning of all phone numbers used on the Tellme Network.

Co-designed and built a system that provided a common framework for managing the software in the Tellme Network.

Responsible for leading a specialized team of three in addressing complex and critical engineering endeavors.

EDUCATION

(7 years)

George Washington University - Washington, DC

Bachelor of Arts, American Literature

Extended professional experience, references, and code samples available by request.